Oh, Congressman Romero,
I just wanted to see you one last time
before I leave.
I don't believe
there's anything left to be said.
No, not between us. Not any longer.
I just wanted to thank you for...
your tenacity.
Whatever you're up to,
you won't get away with it.
Maybe I already have.
The committee will continue its work.
We'll recommend charges to DOJ.
Rochelle.
Such a lovely name.
Tell me how much you don't want that
to end up in the press.
And then shut this committee down.
No deals.
Mr. President! Mr. President!
How could you?
- How could you not warn me?
- To protect you.
- I was protecting you.
- You should take your hands off me.
No, look, I understand
if you feel broadsided.
- I don't care about feelings, Francis.
- But listen to me...
- Look, Claire, listen to me.
- You made me look absolutely ridiculous.
- Ill-prepared and ignorant.
- No! Claire.
- We have one rule, Francis. One rule.
- No, not anymore.
Not anymore. We don't.
I cannot be your ally
if I don't know what you're thinking.
Listen, Claire. It would have never ended.
All right, fine, we got to stop judiciary,
but other committees would have sprung up,
just to keep the charges going.
Oversight, Armed Services,
Foreign Affairs, Intelligence.
It would have gone on and on.
- Years and years of investigation.
- I don't care.
You should have talked to me,
instead of making
a last-minute decision like this.
I didn't.
I created this confusion
in order to take advantage of it.
Everything that has happened...
was planned.
Since when?
Since before Elysian Fields.
But it was at Elysian Fields
that it hit me.
I saw it... almost like a light bulb
going off above my head.
Where does the real power lie?
The power behind the power.
And I understood, Claire,
that we have to think and act differently
than we ever have.
Because it's no longer about
who lives in the White House...
it's about who owns the White House.
This is the presidency.
How much higher can a politician go?
The real power isn't here.
It's beyond here.
It's above it, but still working
in conjunction with it.
Look, Claire,
you and I have always been on the inside.
Trapped. In the bubble.
But going forward...
with my operating on the outside,
in the private sector,
and you working from here...
we can own this house together.
Don't you see? I've designed this.
I wanted you to be the president.
I've made you the president.
Am I supposed to say thank you?
No.
But you will have to pardon me.
Pardon me for all of my crimes.
As the president,
you're the only one who can.
Francis, I could be impeached
if I do that.
No, no. Look, Davis and Usher,
they're in a position to protect you.
- They want you to succeed.
- We can be sure of nothing, Francis.
Everything going on with Doug,
the leak still in the White House...
No, that was me, too.
- What?
- I'm the leak.
I've been feeding information
to Tom Hammerschmidt
for months with Doug's help.
That doesn't make any sense, Francis.
Claire, when you bring yourself down
before someone else can,
you control the way it happens.
This was the only path
to get us to this moment
where you and I can own it all.
Get rid of the surveillance.
Erase it. Shut everything down.
Anything you and Doug were up to.
All right.
But you have to pardon me first.
And, at the right time, Doug.
Or we could both go to prison.
I killed Tom.
I killed Tom Yates. He's dead.
And I had Mark clean it up.
So it will never make its way back to us.
Well, then I guess we both did
what we had to.
- Did you know he was gonna do this?
- No.
- Because this is bad, Claire.
- This is very... very bad.
My God!
What is it with you two?
- If there's something on your mind, say...
- In my house?
You left him in my house?!
Lower your voice,
or at least change your tone.
Did you take care of it?
Yes, that's what I do.
Then thank you, and well done.
Now let's get back
to what's in front of us.
Does he even want you to be here, Claire?
Mark, please. What I need right now
is your political calculus.
He has put you, he has put all of us,
in an impossible position.
You see that?
If you don't handle this correctly,
you do not recover from it.
This is about continuity of government.
Informing NATO, informing world leaders.
We should have had ambassadors on call.
Joint Chiefs of Staff,
the National Security...
Even Nixon did that!
I'm ready to hand it over,
but I want to be assured
that no matter what,
Macallan's death is not related to me.
That can be taken care of.
- I want what you have of mine.
- Okay.
That's what you'll get.
And I want to be Chief of Staff.
Well, I don't think that's a problem.
I'm glad you're asking for what you want.
Doug Stamper would do anything
for the president.
He saw a threat in Zoe Barnes,
who the president was involved with.
And he took care of it.
He's threatened my life
on numerous occasions.
- But to go back to my question...
- No, ma'am.
I don't think the president knew
what Doug was up to.
Not at all.
Mr. Hammerschmidt.
I've been meaning to call you.
Sean.
As you can tell, I work here now.
I'm shaking your hand right now
because I believe in social graces.
You're lost.
- I don't think so.
- No, you are.
No, not at all.
This is what you wanted?
A job in a corrupt administration?
Presidency in ruin?
I'm in the White House. Not out there,
wondering what it's like in here.
Not for long.
Once you're in, you're in.
It's the American way.
- Mr. Stamper will see you now.
- Thank you.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
When I asked for this meeting,
I had no idea
the president would be signing
his resignation this evening.
And I, this morning.
- I heard a rumor you might.
- Now it's confirmed.
Mr. Stamper...
Yeah, please. You can call me Doug.
I'd rather not,
for the sake of this interview.
I want you to know
this will not be off the record,
or on background.
I do know Lisa Williams.
I met her a couple years ago.
Okay.
But before we get to anything else...
did President Underwood,
when he was congressman, kill Zoe Barnes?
No.
Mr. Stamper...
did you kill Zoe Barnes?
I'm not prepared to answer that question.
You understand I can use
your refusal in print.
Yes.
Were you on the Cathedral Heights
D.C. Metro platform
the day of Zoe's death?
Any questions regarding Zoe Barnes,
you need to speak with my attorneys.
Did Zoe Barnes make a call
to Francis Underwood
from a burner phone
when he was congressman?
- Why would you ask me that?
- Why won't you answer?
I almost always answer
the president's phone.
Calls, texts...
Do you have any knowledge of those texts?
I'm not prepared to comment on that.
Then this conversation is over.
Have a good day.
One last thing.
Did you send me two birthday cards?
No.
Slàinte mhath.
That's Scottish Gaelic.
It means "good health."
My father's kind of obsessed.
And he traced our line of Graysons
back to, like, 16th century or something.
Hmm. Well, if we ever needed a drink
in the middle of the day...
It went well with the US attorney.
It's tragic.
Our hearts are just broken
at the thought of what Doug did.
I don't know what happened to him.
I guess somewhere along the line...
When will, uh,
he be announcing his resignation?
- It's happening this afternoon.
- Oh, of course.
And, Seth, you'll need to resign as well.
- Uh... Um, I thought that, uh...
- I know, but think about this.
I need to establish my own team. Publicly.
And there's no avoiding how tied
you and Doug are to Francis at this point.
So, it's really just waiting
for the dust to settle. That's all.
Why does it feel like you're telling me
my career is over, Madam Vice President?
No, I'm just saying, you just need
to go away for a little while.
And we'll bring you back into the fold
at a later date, and don't worry.
Look at LeAnn.
She left and now she's back.
Have we ever had a drink together?
Never.
I wanted to hand this to you
while you were still president.
I accept this with a heavy heart.
I had a strategy session
with the attorneys yesterday.
I hope they're treating you well.
You know...
Doug, we're not gonna be able
to see each other for some time now.
So why don't you take something?
- No.
- No, no. Go on. Take something.
Anything. Anything you want.
Even if it's small.
Something you can hold in your hand
to remind you of this place...
until you get back.
You go on.
We're a few hours away
from my official resignation...
and you still have not agreed
to pardon me.
And if you don't,
I will be forced to renege
on that resignation.
That would be outrageous.
Well, it isn't official until I submit
a signed letter.
And what would that do
to the rest of your presidency?
What would be left of it?
Claire, if you don't do it, you're gonna
risk being married to a felon.
And if I do, where does that leave me?
Look, is this really the conversation
you want to be having?
You've trapped me, Francis.
No, I do not accept
that I've done something to you.
I have provided you with an opportunity.
Now, you have said before,
that this is your endgame.
And now, your goal is
within spitting distance
and all you see is betrayal?
I don't buy it.
Stop talking about what I've done to you.
Admit it.
This is what you want.
You were willing to kill for it.
So, Claire, come and take it...
before I take it back.
We'll find the most strategic
time and place.
But I will pardon you, Francis.
For the good of the nation,
we need to disband this committee,
and put this behind us.
The president most likely
would not have survived the hearings.
You could argue that he had no choice
but to resign.
But we can't deny that his testimony
struck a chord.
Well, that may be true.
But how is it that you,
Congressman Romero,
his biggest critic,
are supporting him now?
History.
By the end of the day, the country
will have its first woman president.
Look, I've always been a supporter
of the idea of a woman in the Oval Office.
But when all is said and done,
you do realize that Francis Underwood
will still be sleeping
in the White House tonight?
Isn't this when you pack everything up?
Or at least take the personal things?
I'm not taking anything.
You can do what you want with it.
- When do you meet with the US attorney?
- Day after tomorrow.
I never thought that Frank Underwood
would not be president.
Not really.
You could just run away.
What does that get me?
You're good at taking care of yourself.
That's funny.
Look, I want you to know
that I care for you,
but I don't know how much I can be there.
I think I'm gonna just sit here
for a while.
Yeah, you should.
Uh, the vice president would like you
to leave the White House
before she's sworn in.
She doesn't think it would be a good idea
for word to get out
that you were here when it happened.
I do solemnly swear
that I will faithfully execute
the office of President
of the United States,
and will to the best of my ability
preserve, protect and defend
the Constitution of the United States.
- So help me God.
- Here we are again.
You know, if you ignore
all the pomp and circumstance,
the most perverse thing is
I actually believe in the presidency.
Its importance. What it means
around the world, even symbolically.
But I believe in power even more.
For its own sake.
Gore Vidal once wrote
that power is an end to itself,
and the instinctive urge to prevail...
the most important single human trait.
I've always told myself that
everything I did was for her.
But maybe it wasn't.
Maybe I love power more.
For you, and for any dear to you,
I would do anything.
If my career were of that better kind
that there was any opportunity
or capacity to sacrifice in it,
I would embrace any sacrifice for you
and for those dear to you.
Try to hold me in your mind,
at some quiet times,
as ardent and sincere in this one thing.
The time will come,
the time will not be long in coming,
when new ties will be formed about you.
The ties that will bind you
yet more tenderly and strongly
to the home you so adorn.
The dearest ties that will ever
grace and gladden you.
Oh, Miss Manette,
when the little picture of
a happy father's face looks up in yours...
Good evening.
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen.
My name is Sean Jeffries.
I'm the new deputy director
of communications.
Where's Seth?
Mr. Grayson got called away last minute,
so I'm temporarily filling his shoes.
Uh, I...
I won't be taking any questions. Instead,
I'll be reading from a prepared statement.
A few hours ago,
President Underwood resigned the office
of President of the United States.
And in a private ceremony
attended by staff,
President Claire Underwood was sworn in.
Effective immediately,
she will be assuming the office
of President of the United States.
- Details will be coming shortly...
- You must be so proud of him.
And while President Francis Underwood
couldn't be here today...
Transfer of power happened
three hours ago,
quote, "privately and quietly."
And that's above the fold.
- Anything from DOJ?
- Nothing yet.
No official title to him,
but it's Mark Usher
running the transition.
Okay.
Let's find out who's in and who's out.
The dominoes are falling.
- Now, who's on Romero?
- Here.
- We want the congressman on the record.
- I've got it.
And let's save Macallan for the weekend.
Tom, where are we with Doug Stamper?
There's, uh, something I need to check on.
Slugline, BuzzFeed, half the outlets
in this city are ready to jump on this.
You spoke to him. One on one.
- He didn't actually say he did it.
- He doesn't have to.
Does anyone know what Seth Grayson
said to the US attorney?
Tom?
Two years you've been writing
about this administration.
- This is it.
- I want to follow up, that's all.
I see a beautiful city
and a brilliant people rising
from this abyss.
And in their struggles to be truly free,
in their triumphs and defeats,
through long years to come,
I see the evil of this time
and of the previous time
of which this is the natural birth,
gradually making expiation for itself
and wearing out.
Surface-to-surface missiles
delivered sarin
at about three o'clock in the morning,
our time.
Moscow has already issued a statement
condemning the rebels
for orchestrating
the attack on themselves.
- And did they?
- Of course not.
Petrov will use this
to justify air strikes.
I'd like to show you an image.
This one is coming out of Reuters.
The feeling is most of the press
will be using it by the a.m.
Experience tells me this will resonate
for about three to five days...
which gives us our window.
- Well, we can ready a statement.
- Troops on the ground is the statement.
No, I don't want to do anything
until we find Ahmadi's location.
I'm not sure we should wait on this,
Madam President.
I'd like to remind you
that it was this administration
that introduced the ultimatum.
- You should act on it.
- Yes, but I barely have a team in place.
Well, you can run it
by the former president...
The former president is just that.
- An opportunity has presented itself.
- And I'm trying to take advantage of it.
- Is everyone in the Situation Room?
- As of 20 minutes ago.
So, the timing is bad.
If you pardon him now,
you're associated with his crimes.
Republicans will have a field day.
We need some cover.
Well, that would be
Ahmadi's capture.
- The right VP would help all this.
- Have you had any further thoughts?
My short list is the same.
Westervelt, Clark, Klein.
Klein would be the strongest bulwark
against calls for your impeachment.
- Swallowing poison to stay alive.
- Alive is good.
I don't think I can stomach Klein.
He called me a bitch. I prefer Clark.
Tell me. Before you moved the body,
were you able to close his eyes?
Yes.
Look... I know his opinion
means a lot to you.
Francis.
But having him here, in the White House,
even in the East Wing,
while we're trying to figure this out,
it's hard.
At some point, someone is going to imply
that he is still making the decisions.
That wouldn't be good.
- I'll advise her. She'll come around.
- I hope so.
Because if she doesn't act now,
when it comes to Syria,
her presidency could be in danger.
- And your future in doubt.
- Oh, don't threaten me, Ms. Davis.
I don't threaten.
I just try to remain as clear as possible.
You offered me your services,
and I offered you mine.
You know...
I was here before you
and I'll be here after you.
And regardless of that,
let me remind you...
that nothing is more dangerous than me.
You need to be practical now.
Davis isn't wrong.
We've been trying to get our hands
on Ahmadi for a year, Francis.
- She hasn't delivered.
- Yes, but this isn't about her.
This is about you and coming out
with a strong message
in your first address to the nation.
This is about setting the course
for your presidency.
Be strong, Claire.
Go to war.
But I need you to leave.
Leave the White House.
Yes, I see.
For this pardon to succeed, Francis,
we need to appear to be estranged.
I'm just being strategic.
And where do you suggest I go?
I'm not sure.
The Naval Observatory?
Uh, I think the vice president's
residence is still too close.
I'm sorry, I just...
We can't have anyone think
you're still involved in policy.
Look, if you're having second thoughts,
you should tell me now.
- No. I'm in full agreement.
- 'Cause this is no time to hesitate.
I am not hesitating.
I just believe
if we don't play this correctly,
as far as the public,
my term will be nothing
but survival for both of us.
All right.
I want you to know I'm here if you need...
any advice on policy or...
anything else you might need.
Thank you. I'm going to bed.
No one will ever love you as much as I do.
I hope you know that.
Just as I know that no one
will ever love me... like you.
"Under the porcelain frog."
The answers are case-sensitive and exact.
You won't get a second chance.
- And the middle one?
- My favorite baseball player?
"Wade Boggs." Two G's.
And the last? "What did you leave
in that hotel room in Austin?"
Where is my gun?
Here you go.
What guarantees do I have?
I gave you your gun back.
But what made you give it to him?
I'm curious.
I thought he was in danger.
And now you think what?
That is what I'm asking.
As long as I'm around,
you'll be a part of this administration.
We both know too much about Aidan.
And Claire knows how loyal you are.
I'm sure of it.
So, what did you leave
in that hotel room in Austin?
A bracelet.
Oh, that's too bad.
You know, I finally got a look at what
Macallan passed on to Ms. Harvey.
I was shocked to realize the degree
to which you and your husband
stole this election.
I need to be honest with you.
I've been in talks with him about
helping him start a foundation
of some kind.
In exchange for influence over you.
Interesting.
I'm trying to help you
navigate this transition.
Who are you to me?
Who do you want me to be?
That's not a good answer.
You're the first woman President
of the United States.
All you've had to swallow,
the sacrifices, the compromises.
You're gonna want to isolate yourself.
Not trust anyone.
But that's exactly what you're gonna need.
Someone to tell you what's what.
And is that person you?
Is it?
I don't think there's anything
I could say that would convince you
if you don't already feel it.
Ms. Davis,
you are asking me to start a war.
And you seem to deliver on promises
when it suits you.
So forgive me
if I question your intentions.
I like you.
I like being around you.
And sometimes that makes me
less effective than I should be.
Pardoning or not pardoning your husband,
in either case, he's a liability.
If it's not treated properly...
your husband's liver could fail him
at any time.
It's not the kind of thing I could do.
But I could find someone, or...
I... I don't know if you realize, but...
even something like gelsemium
can be lethal in higher doses.
My husband's health is just fine.
I'll continue to work with him.
Follow your lead.
Here's my client's passport.
- There's a few things we want to go over.
- That we haven't already?
No cuffs, when you walk him out of here.
I need to be sure.
Oh, come on, James,
we aren't gonna play that on this.
You have some very good friends,
Mr. Stamper,
to keep the press out of this.
You will walk out of here
like a gentleman.
We want him in front of the judge
within 12 hours.
We don't even know
if we're gonna charge him yet.
I did it.
Let's get going.
Who do you have on her cabinet?
Right now, they're just suggestions.
Oh, come on. We both know how this works.
You've already made your choices.
You wouldn't be worth your salt
if you hadn't.
I just want you to run them by me first.
Look, I can make this transition
easy for you or not.
And a word of advice.
She's gonna need some friendly faces
looking at her across that table.
There'll be a few...
who will smile as required.
Would you look at this?
Both Special Forces. Former.
They know how to forget,
so you don't have to worry about them.
And the body?
It's on ice.
I just made contact with Nasser.
We have secured the location of Ahmadi.
- I'll assemble the team.
- I called Admiral Dale already.
So we have some decisions to make.
Once we have troops on the ground,
we'll need to take a close look
at who we're considering for your cabinet.
You'll need a team around you
with wartime experience.
I have some suggestions
I've passed on to Mark.
I think Deputy Director of the CIA,
Marcy Siegerson,
would make a terrific Secretary of State.
Someone I could easily liaison with.
Well, I was hoping that you would be
on my cabinet, in some capacity.
I'll be operating out of the region.
It's where my strength lies.
There are better people
who can take it from here,
advise you on the home front.
And Ms. Harvey, LeAnn,
we need to move you.
Uh, just for now, of course.
- It was my understanding that...
- Right now a more seasoned Chief of Staff
would send a strong message to
the Congress and to the nation. For now.
She'll do it. She'll send in the troops.
I'll be in Dubai by tomorrow afternoon.
And our deal stays in place.
Yeah, hold on a second.
- Ready?
- Go ahead.
Yes. Ms. Harvey has her gun back.
Macallan's files are with the president.
Any hard evidence connecting you
to the election...
is in her hands.
Then LeAnn's job is done.
If you have anything to say,
now is the time.
What do you think happened?
I'd prefer you tell me that.
Humor me. You asked for this meeting.
What do you think happened?
I believe Zoe Barnes was investigating
a relationship you were having
with Rachel Posner.
And somehow, that knowledge would endanger
Francis Underwood,
who you would do anything for.
But did anyone think
about the life of Zoe Barnes?
You know,
you think you can erase something.
Then you find out that's not possible.
Tom, my attorneys didn't even want me
to speak with you.
I'm sorry,
there's just nothing more to say here.
I don't know what happened
to Rachel Posner.
But I don't believe you killed Zoe Barnes.
Is this you in this video?
Looks like me.
I've thought long and hard, Francis.
Barely slept.
That's the job.
I'm going to send in troops.
I'll be announcing it tomorrow night.
I think you're doing the right thing.
Do you hate it here?
Oh, you know I don't like hotels.
An approximation of home
just to remind you you're not there.
Well, we don't live in a home.
We live in a house,
borrowed and temporary.
Something in your eye. A look.
It's changed.
We're the same now, you and I.
- How so?
- You know how.
It's been a long time
since I surprised myself.
You'll recover.
You're the most powerful woman
in the world, Claire.
Comfort pales by comparison.
I'll announce it during the speech,
after the troops.
A full and unconditional pardon...
for Francis Underwood and any crimes
he might have committed
against the United States while president.
I'm glad to hear that.
It was never in doubt.
I just needed to think about how.
So how long does this arrangement last?
For the time being.
How did we get here, Francis?
Oh, let it go. It's done.
Oh, and one word of advice.
Whomever Usher offers up to you
as vice president,
that's the person
that you're really gonna have to watch.
I won't choose anyone I can't manage.
Southwest corner
of the building. Maintain visual.
Copy that.
Frag out!
There's Ahmadi.
I have visual on Ahmadi.
- I see him.
- Go, go! Fire!
I made a terrible mistake.
What did you do?
I don't even know what I'm doing here.
I, uh...
This morning I started driving.
I... I got scared.
Anyway, I'm on my way back.
Can I come see you?
Yes, please.
Sometimes you don't have to watch
the whole movie to know how it ends.
The speech is gonna play well
with both parties.
Where are we with the Republicans?
Trading names
when it comes to your cabinet.
We have our generals, which is good.
Some corporate types, outsiders.
Make you seem like a renegade.
Corporate, from where?
Oil, banking, mostly. Some tech.
Occasional D.C. lifer sprinkled
into the mix
to make sure the trains run on time.
I was going over our list
for vice president.
Yeah. Hold on.
Uh, this will seem unexpected,
but a lot of the people
I spoke to suggested me.
You're not a politician.
Exactly.
But I could be by your side.
Most of the Hill and the Senate
would not come near us.
- I'll take it into consideration.
- It's beyond that. You'll need me.
Excuse me?
I can help. Look...
It is the way
to keep you in power.
And keep your secrets.
Good evening.
I'm here to report to the American people
and the world
that early this morning, Special Forces
killed the ICO terrorist Ahmed Al Ahmadi.
We got him.
Now, there comes a time
in every president's tenure
when he or she must face the question
of whether or not
to send young American soldiers
into harm's way.
In my case...
that time has fallen within
the very first days of my presidency.
Russian President Viktor Petrov
collaborated with the Chinese
on illegal oil exploration in Antarctica.
Recently, we have learned
that he has sent troops
to fight alongside the Syrian regime,
assisting them in the destruction
of the Syrian nation.
These forces are using chemical weapons
on their own people,
torturing the opposition, and starving
huge segments of the population.
The Syrians are a people besieged.
Let them not also be forgotten.
The time has come for our outrage
to be turned into action.
Five months ago, my husband addressed
the House of Representatives
and asked them to declare war on ICO.
Congress failed him.
Congress failed you.
ICO extremists want democracy
and America itself to die a fiery death.
We cannot allow that to happen.
We can't wait for Congress any longer.
We gave Congress every chance.
She isn't going to say it.
Now, history judges every leader,
every president,
by how he or she treats
his or her own people.
A regime that would target hospitals,
refugee camps,
schools or bread lines in order
to retain power must be confronted.
A leader that would sacrifice the physical
and emotional well-being of his citizens,
that would treat his people as pawns,
just to stay in power? Well...
that leader needs to be stopped.
If she doesn't pardon me...
I'll kill her.
Thank you
and God bless this great country.
Well, the calls are coming in already.
Well done.
This'll be a good night for you.
Nothing from Moscow yet.
Right now I just need some time to myself.
Do you know Tom Yates?
Uh, not personally. Why?
He hasn't been around in a while.
I don't know, forget it.
What?
I've been calling him.
And he usually answers.
We demand justice,
we demand peace!
No more war in the Middle East!
We demand justice, we demand peace!
We demand justice, we demand peace...
The anti-war demonstrations
outside the White House
finally got out of hand.
You've reached
LeAnn Harvey. Please leave a message.
One of the protesters
made his way over the gates.
As he was running across
the White House lawn,
Secret Service agents moved in,
tragically shooting and killing the man.
You've reached
LeAnn Harvey. Please leave a message.
Hey, where are you?
I'm sorry, ma'am,
it's just not possible tonight.
We can't secure the run.
The level of threat at this point
is just too high.
- Okay. Thank you.
- Yes, ma'am.
My turn.
Sync and corrections by btsix
www.addic7ed.com
www.tvsubtitles.net